<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE message:feed PUBLIC '-//tsert.com//DTD Packager 1.0.0//EN' 'message.dtd' [
<!ENTITY copyright 'Copyright 2014, Tsert.com, All Rights Reserved.'>
]>
<message
    xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink'
    xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
    xmlns:tsert='http://tsert.com/dtd/tsert/'
    xmlns:attr='http://tsert.com/dtd/css/'
    xmlns:message='http://tsert.com/dtd/message/' message:version='1.0.0'>

<message:header>
	<identifier>Breeze::OS Distro News</identifier>
	<title>News for Slackware derivative</title>
	<storage>permanent</storage>
	<submission>manual</submission>
	<engine>brzpkg v2.0.0</engine>
	<urgency>normal</urgency>
	<sender url='www.breezeos.com' identifier='dev@breezeos.com'/>
</message:header>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-09-08</identifier>
<title>Release of Breeze::OS v1.0</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Initial release of the Breeze::OS GNU/Linux distribution which is based
on the Slackware 14.1 release. Only the Xfce and KDE flavors are offered
for the initial release. Each flavor comes with either, the i486 or PAE
linux kernels. All ISO(s) can be downloaded from our website
at http://tsert.com/breeze/download.html
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-10-02</identifier>
<title>X11/Xorg Bug Report for Breeze::OS v1.0</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
A weird bug has surfaced in our X11 installation. The bug seems to cause
the X procotol for mouse inputs, to grab focus in a particular window; and,
to refuse to release it. The same bug appears in all our installations, and
on several computers. We have not succeeded in resolving the issue.

A, temporary, solution is to logout, and login a second time; which seems to
make the X11 installation more stable.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-12-17</identifier>
<title>Upcoming Release of Breeze::OS v1.1</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
The next release of the Breeze::OS GNU/Linux distribution, which is still
based on the Slackware 14.1 release; will be available for download in
January 2015.

The Mate flavor, taken from the Salix repositories, was added to the set of
available flavors, i.e. Xfce and KDE.

Each flavor comes with either, the i486 or PAE Linux kernels.
All ISO(s) will be available for download from our website at
http://tsert.com/breeze/download.html or from SourceForge at
http://breezeos.sourceforge.net.

New features have been added to the package manager. Other features
have been removed; such as, updating from the current repository.

It is now easier to update packages, just by issuing the command:
	't-pkg -U &lt;package name&gt;'
It is no longer necessary to wait for an RSS/Message feed from our website.
It is also easier to upgrade, just by issuing the command 't-pkg --upgrade'.

</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-12-27</identifier>
<title>Booting problems with uploaded ISOs for i486 kernels</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
For some reasons, the ISO(s), which were burned with non-PAE i486 kernels,
no longer are able to boot. Booting simply stops after the Linux logo is
displayed. The ISO(s), which were burned with PAE i486 kernels, do boot; but,
the X11 installer seizes, refusing to recognize keyboard and mouse inputs.

The above problems were detected; because, we were unable to burn working
PAE and non-PAE i486 ISO(s) for release 1.1; even though, the same code
base of our installer was being used.

It is what caused us to examine the ISO(s) released in September 8, 2014.
As a consequence, we may reboot v1.0, by turning v1.1 into v1.0.

The problem listed above with the non-PAE kernels does not occur; when the
same kernel is used to boot within a normal desktop environment.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-12-30</identifier>
<title>Major VFS problem detected</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
In our installer development environment, we detected a weird filesystem
bug, which caused files to revert to previous versions. At first, we thought
that a failing drive was the problem; but, since the problem was detected
on all our computers running Linux, we could only assume that a VFS bug was
the culprit. Our computers are running Debian wheezy, Slackware 14.0, and
Slackware 14.1, respectively.

The problem was detected by randomizing the source code file names, and
obfuscating the source code within the files, of our installer. We then,
created a compilation folder, and iteratively copied the randomized and
obfuscated source code files onto the same folder, on every compilation.

After a few iterations, the Gnu make compilation tool would encounter an
error, because of undefined symbols, which could only be found in a previous
version of an obfuscated source code file. This problem definitely proved
that the VFS was the culprit. Somehow the same inode is being re-used, as
a new file gets created.

We will upload a script to detect the problem in a few weeks, as we release
the rebooted version 1.0 of our Breeze::OS distro.

</content-body>
</message:update>
</message>
