<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE message:feed PUBLIC '-//tsert.com//DTD Packager 1.0.0//EN' 'message.dtd' [
<!ENTITY copyright 'Copyright 2014, Tsert.com, All Rights Reserved.'>
]>
<message
    xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink'
    xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
    xmlns:tsert='http://tsert.com/dtd/tsert/'
    xmlns:attr='http://tsert.com/dtd/css/'
    xmlns:message='http://tsert.com/dtd/message/' message:version='1.0.0'>

<message:header>
	<identifier>Breeze::OS Distro News</identifier>
	<title>News for Slackware derivative</title>
	<storage>permanent</storage>
	<submission>manual</submission>
	<engine>brzpkg v2.3.0</engine>
	<urgency>normal</urgency>
	<sender url='www.breezeos.com' identifier='dev@breezeos.com'/>
</message:header>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-09-08</identifier>
<title>Release of Breeze::OS v1.0</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Initial release of the Breeze::OS GNU/Linux distribution which is based
on the Slackware 14.1 release. Only the Xfce and KDE flavors are offered
for the initial release. Each flavor comes with either, the i486 or PAE
linux kernels. All ISO(s) can be downloaded from our website
at http://tsert.com/breeze/download.html
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-10-02</identifier>
<title>X11/Xorg Bug Report for Breeze::OS v1.0</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
A weird bug has surfaced in our X11 installation. The bug seems to cause
the X procotol for mouse inputs, to grab focus in a particular window; and,
to refuse to release it. The same bug appears in all our installations, and
on several computers. We have not succeeded in resolving the issue.

A, temporary, solution is to logout, and login a second time; which seems to
make the X11 installation more stable.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-12-17</identifier>
<title>Upcoming release of Breeze::OS v1.1</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
The next release of the Breeze::OS GNU/Linux distribution, which is still
based on the Slackware 14.1 release; will be available for download in
January 2015.

The Mate flavor, taken from the Salix repositories, was added to the set of
available flavors, i.e. Xfce and KDE.

Each flavor comes with either, the i486 or PAE Linux kernels.
All ISO(s) will be available for download from our website at
http://tsert.com/breeze/download.html or from SourceForge at
http://breezeos.sourceforge.net.

New features have been added to the package manager. Other features
have been removed; such as, updating from the current repository.

It is now easier to update packages, just by issuing the command:
	't-pkg -U &lt;package name&gt;'
It is no longer necessary to wait for an RSS/Message feed from our website.
It is also easier to upgrade, just by issuing the command 't-pkg --upgrade'.

</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-12-27</identifier>
<title>Booting problems with uploaded ISOs for i486 kernels</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
For some reasons, the ISO(s), which were burned with non-PAE i486 kernels,
no longer are able to boot. Booting simply stops after the Linux logo is
displayed. The ISO(s), which were burned with PAE i486 kernels, do boot; but,
the X11 installer seizes, refusing to recognize keyboard and mouse inputs.

The above problems were detected; because, we were unable to burn working
PAE and non-PAE i486 ISO(s) for release 1.1; even though, the same code
base of our installer was being used.

It is what caused us to examine the ISO(s) released in September 8, 2014.
As a consequence, we may reboot v1.0, by turning v1.1 into v1.0.

The problem listed above with the non-PAE kernels does not occur; when the
same kernel is used to boot within a normal desktop environment.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2014-12-30</identifier>
<title>Major VFS problem detected</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
In our installer development environment, we detected a weird filesystem
bug, which caused files to revert to previous versions. At first, we thought
that a failing drive was the problem; but, since the problem was detected
on all our computers running Linux, we could only assume that a VFS bug was
the culprit. Our computers are running Debian wheezy, Slackware 14.0, and
Slackware 14.1, respectively.

The problem was detected by randomizing the source code file names, and
obfuscating the source code within the files, of our installer. We then,
created a compilation folder, and iteratively copied the randomized and
obfuscated source code files onto the same folder, on every compilation.

After a few iterations, the Gnu make compilation tool would encounter an
error, because of undefined symbols, which could only be found in a previous
version of an obfuscated source code file. This problem definitely proved
that the VFS was the culprit. Somehow the same inode is being re-used, as
a new file gets created.

We will upload a script to detect the problem in a few weeks, as we release
the rebooted version 1.0 of our Breeze::OS distro.

</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2015-01-17</identifier>
<title>Another extremely weird bug !</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
The code, below, which was compiled with GCC 4.7.1 and GCC 4.8.2
yielded the same correct results with lower_bound indicating the
right entry in the std::vector of items; even though  it should have
failed, because the wrong constructor for SetItem was being called.
After rebooting the system, the right behavior was then exhibited;
the call failed as expected.

I have currently no explanation for the bug. Again the bug appeared
on two separate computers; one running Slackware 14.0, and the other
Slackware 14.1.

bool Set::search(const String&amp; name, SetItem **item) const
{
	SetItem key( name );
	LessThan less( "id" );

	const_iterator it = std::lower_bound( begin(), end(), &amp;key, less );

	if (it != Set::end()) {
		String found((*it)->getName());

		std::cout &lt;&lt; found &lt;&lt; "\n";

		if (found == name) {
			(*item) = (*it);
			return true;
		}
	}
	return false;
}
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2015-02-01</identifier>
<title>Update News (version 1.1)</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
A slight delay in the release of version 1.1; we decided to offer
the most up-to-date Slackware 14.1 patches. 

We also added a simpler way to manage services, with the use of
a service manager, called brzctl. The service manager is for now,
just a managing application; but, we intend to turn it into an
OpenRC-type daemon and service manager in the future. 

The operations allowed by brzctl are: enabling and disabling services,
adding and removing services, starting, stopping, and reloading services,
and setting options for services.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2015-03-09</identifier>
<title>Update News (version 1.1)</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Point release 1.1 of the Breeze::OS GNU/Linux distribution which is based
on the Slackware 14.1 release. The Xfce, KDE, and Mate flavors are offered.
The Mate flavor is from the Salix repositories.

No ISO(s), for version 1.1, are currently available; because of the booting
problem mentioned in the news item '2014-12-27'. We decided in the meantime
to try a Live-DVD and a netinstall release for April 2015.

First download the upgrade script and signature in the same folder.
   wget http://www.breezeos.com/distfiles/slackware/i486/1.1/brz-upgrade.sh
   wget http://www.breezeos.com/distfiles/slackware/i486/1.1/brz-upgrade.sh.asc

Then, invoke the script with the option '-slack' if you are upgrading from
a Slackware 14.0/14.1 distro; or without option, if you have our distro
installed on your computer.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2016-04-07</identifier>
<title>Upcoming release of 64-bit version of Breeze::OS</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
The upcoming release of the &lt;b>64-bit&lt;/b> Breeze::OS GNU/Linux, based on
the Slackware64 14.1 release; will be available for download in April 2016.

In most part, the same set of packages that are offered on the &lt;b>32-bit&lt;/b> release
are also offered in the &lt;b>64-bit&lt;/b> release; including, our own set of tools
and applications.

A &lt;b>Live DVD&lt;/b>, with scripts derived from Slackware-Live, is being prepared.
The scripts, renamed &lt;i>BreezeOS-Live&lt;/i>, will be hosted on GitHub.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2016-04-11</identifier>
<title>Release of Breeze::OS v1.2</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
This release is the &lt;b>last and long-term&lt;/b> point release for versions 1.x; and it
is still based on the Slackware 14.1 release, with the Xfce, KDE, and Mate
desktops being offered, It contains packages, i.e. &lt;i>OpenOffice 4.1.2&lt;/i>, which were
updated for either enhancements, bugs, or security issues. It also contains a new
display manager called &lt;b>brzdm&lt;/b> derived from &lt;b>Slim&lt;/b>. The source code for &lt;b>brzdm&lt;/b> will be
hosted at https://www.github.com. The Linux kernel 4.1.17 has also been added.

The main new features, which have been added to the package manager, are the
facility to &lt;b>websync&lt;/b> your installation with updated binary packages; as well as,
the capability to compile from source using &lt;i>slackbuilds&lt;/i>. An additional feature
was added to view &lt;b>security advisory&lt;/b> from &lt;b>Slackware&lt;/b>. Each package, by default,
has its checksum and &lt;i>GnuPG&lt;/i> signature verified; you, now, must &lt;b>turn off&lt;/b>
verification, when desired.

You can, now, just issue the command &lt;b>brzpkg --websync&lt;/b> to download and install
updated binary packages; &lt;b>brzpkg -A&lt;/b> to view security advisory news; and,
&lt;b>brzpkg -B &lt;pkg>&lt;/b> or &lt;b>brzpkg -I -b &lt;pkg>&lt;/b> to install a package from source.

Conflict resolution was not done for the &lt;b>slackbuilds&lt;/b> packages; therefore,
you must check for conflicts between packages yourself, before compiling.

I you have not upgraded to version 1.1; you must first execute the following:
   wget http://www.breezeos.com/distfiles/slackware/i486/1.2/brz-upgrade.sh
   wget http://www.breezeos.com/distfiles/slackware/i486/1.2/brz-upgrade.sh.asc

Then, invoke the script with the option '-slack' if you are upgrading from
a Slackware 14.0/14.1 distro; or without option, if you have our distro
installed on your computer.

If you are running our distro; then, you &lt;b>must first update&lt;/b> the packager itself,
by invoking 'brzpkg --update brzpkg'; then, 'brzpkg --force --upgrade 1.2' to
proceed with the upgrade.

CD ISO(s), for version 1.2, will be made available in the Spring of 2016.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2016-04-20</identifier>
<title>Release of Breeze::OS LiveDVD 1.2RC1</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
LiveDVD Release Candidate [RC1] for version 1.2, is now available.

The booting problem mentioned in the news item &lt;b>2014-12-27&lt;/b> was not resolved.
We decided to offer a Live-DVD, instead of sticking to releases of CD ISO flavors.
This version is not yet production ready; because, the package installer has not
yet been thoroughly tested; and the LiveDVD is being released, mainly, as a
demonstration DVD. 

Use the script d-iso2usb.sh to burn a persistent version of the LiveDVD on a USB key.
The command is: &lt;b>d-iso2usb.sh -p -v -i breezeos-live-1.2RC1-i486.iso -o &lt;i>/dev/sdb&lt;/i>&lt;/b>
The path &lt;b>/dev/sdb&lt;/b> points to your USB device; and, may be different on your computer.
Use &lt;b>lsblk -f&lt;/b> to be sure, before using the script &lt;b>d-iso2usb.sh&lt;/b>.

The script, used to create the LiveDVD, has been derived from liveslak-0.8.0; and
is using our package management application &lt;b>brzpkg&lt;/b>. It will be hosted
on GitHub as livebrz-0.9.0.

The package installer is called &lt;b>brzinst&lt;/b> and can be invoked from a
terminal window, as root. The command is &lt;b>brzinst --appmode&lt;/b>. 

Type &lt;i>&lt;b>live&lt;/b>&lt;/i> for both the username and password to login.

If you encounter a mouse or keyboard freeze problem, while using &lt;b>brzinst&lt;/b>; just,
press CTL+ALT-Delete to restart X11. The problem may be due to an ACPI glitch,
or a bug in X11 (not yet resolved).

The URLs for the LiveDVD are:
	https://sourceforge.net/projects/breezeos/files/slackware/iso/i486/1.2/breezeos-live-1.2RC1-i486.iso
	https://sourceforge.net/projects/breezeos/files/slackware/iso/i486/1.2/breezeos-live-1.2RC1-i486.iso.checksums
	https://sourceforge.net/projects/breezeos/files/slackware/iso/i486/1.2/d-iso2usb.sh

</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2017-04-27-01</identifier>
<title>Release of Breeze::OS V2.0 [amd64]</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Release of version 2.0 of the Breeze::OS 64-bit GNU/Linux distribution, which
is based on the Slackware64 14.2 release. The Xfce [4.12], Mate [1.16], and KDE
[4.14.3] desktops are offered.

The Live DVD ISO is available for download at https://breezeos.sourceforge.io.

The &lt;b>Breeze::OS installer &lt;i>brzinst&lt;/i>&lt;/b>, now includes an encryption page,
allowing you to setup disk encryption for your installation. It can also be
invoked, as just another session, by using our display manager &lt;b>brzdm&lt;/b>.

The package manager is now, also offered in a self-run package; allowing it to
be run independently of the installed packages. You can download it; and
execute it in console mode. It is located at
    https://breezeos.sourceforge.io/distfiles/slackware/amd64/2.0/brzpkg-x64.run

</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2017-04-27-02</identifier>
<title>Release of Breeze::OS v1.0 [amd64]</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Release of version 1.0 of the Breeze::OS 64-bit GNU/Linux distribution, which
is based on the Slackware64 14.1 release. The Xfce [4.10], Mate [1.8], and KDE
[4.10.5] desktops are offered.

The Live DVD ISO is available for download at https://breezeos.sourceforge.io.

We decided to release version one, based on Slackware 14.1; because,
of the migration to &lt;b>pulseaudio&lt;/b> for multimedia for version 2.0.

The &lt;b>Breeze::OS installer &lt;i>brzinst&lt;/i>&lt;/b>, now includes an encryption page,
allowing you to setup disk encryption for your installation. It can also be
invoked, as just another session, by using our display manager &lt;b>brzdm&lt;/b>.

The package manager is now, also offered in a self-run package; allowing it to
be run independently of the installed packages. You can download it; and
execute it in console mode. It is located at
    https://breezeos.sourceforge.io/distfiles/slackware/amd64/1.0/brzpkg-x64.run

</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2017-04-27-03</identifier>
<title>Point Release version 1.3 [i486]</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
This point release becomes the new &lt;b>long-term&lt;/b> release for versions
1.x [32-bit], which is based on the Slackware 14.1 release. The Xfce [4.10],
Mate [1.8], and KDE [4.10.5] desktops are offered.

A Live DVD ISO is available for download at https://breezeos.sourceforge.io.

The &lt;b>Breeze::OS installer &lt;i>brzinst&lt;/i>&lt;/b>, now includes an encryption page,
allowing you to setup disk encryption for your installation. It can also be
invoked, as just another session, by using our display manager &lt;b>brzdm&lt;/b>.

The package manager is now, also offered in a self-run package; allowing it to
be run independently of the installed packages. You can download it; and
execute it in console mode. It is located at
     https://breezeos.sourceforge.io/distfiles/slackware/i486/1.3/brzpkg-x32.run

</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2018-04-03</identifier>
<title>Preliminary Release Date</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
A preliminary date for the new releases of our distro is June 11, 2018.
All releases will contain the spectre-fixed kernels for the baseline.

Updated kernels for the Slackware versions can be downloaded
by using the update command of the package manager.

People who subscribe to our distro, will get in addition, the first release
of our Gtk2-based desktop, named Carbon2 [C2].

Depending on the amount of donations, further releases of the desktop
using different toolkits [FOX, GTK3, QT4, QT5], may be delayed or accelerated.

The Java version is too be a commercial only release, preliminary called
Carbon14 [C14].
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2018-05-15</identifier>
<title>Portal Announcement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Announcing the opening of our Breeze::OS shop, which is attached
to our main company portal Glyph.Cloud. You will be able to purchase
cd-roms or flash drives, containing the latest releases of our distribution.
You will also be able to register to our Breeze::OS subscriptions.
Other services will also be offered on the Glyph.Cloud portal.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2018-05-31</identifier>
<title>Portal Announcement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Our Breeze::OS Glyph.Cloud shop is still under construction.
We are currently setting up a public key creation feature, to
secure communications with our prospective clients.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2018-06-17</identifier>
<title>Portal Announcement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Announcing that in two weeks; all the work underway to secure our website will be complete.
Our Breeze::OS shop will then be put online and ready for business. As previously mentioned,
our Breeze::OS shop is attached to our main company portal Glyph.Cloud.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2018-06-21</identifier>
<title>Portal Announcement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Update to the previous post:
After announcing that in two weeks, all the work underway to secure our website will be complete;
a possible sabotage of our website and server setup might have taken place. A few more days will
be required to ascertain to how the sabotage migh t have taken place.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2018-07-12</identifier>
<title>Distro Announcement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
An updated date for the new releases of our distro is July 29, 2018.
Releases will contain the spectre-fixed kernels for the baseline.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2018-08-29</identifier>
<title>Distro Announcement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Decided to select OpenRC as the Breeze::OS default init system.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2018-12-05</identifier>
<title>Distro Announcement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Modified the look-and-feel of the Breeze::OS packager.
http://www.breezeos.com/images/brzpkg-gui.jpg

Developed a curses interface to the Breeze::OS packager.
http://www.breezeos.com/images/brzpkg-curses.jpg
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2019-01-13</identifier>
<title>Distro Annoucement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Added a feature to the package manager which set the access permissions
on some system folders; such as /usr/lib, to read-only on exit.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2019-04-01</identifier>
<title>Distro Annoucement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Added aria2c as another downloading utility, in addition to wget and curl.
The aria2c functionality will first be added to the package manager.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2019-04-27</identifier>
<title>Distro Annoucement</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Because of an Expose bug in the Xorg server [ devuan ], modified the Login
manager brzdm. Simplified the display of widgets, text and icons.
</content-body>
</message:update>

<message:update>
<identifier>2019-10-17</identifier>
<title>Release of Breeze::OS V2.1 [amd64]</title>
<derivative>slackware</derivative>
<source>www.breezeos.com</source>
<content-type>text/plain</content-type>
<content-charset>UTF-8</content-charset>
<content-body>
Release of version 2.1 of the Breeze::OS 64-bit GNU/Linux distribution, which
is based on the Slackware64 14.2 release. The Xfce [4.12], Mate [1.16],
Lxde [0.99.2], and KDE [4.14.3] desktops are offered.

The Live DVD ISO will be available for download at https://breezeos.sourceforge.io.

Use the script named d-make-liveusb.sh to write the ISO to a USB flash drive.

The default &lt;b>Breeze::OS init.d system&lt;/b> is now &lt;b>&lt;i>OpenRC&lt;/i>&lt;/b>.

The &lt;b>Breeze::OS installer &lt;i>brzinst&lt;/i>&lt;/b>, now includes an encryption page,
allowing you to setup disk encryption for your installation. It can also be
invoked, as just another session, by using our display manager &lt;b>brzdm&lt;/b>.

The package manager is now, also offered in a self-run package; allowing it to
be run independently of the installed packages. You can download it; and
execute it in console mode. It is located at
    https://breezeos.sourceforge.io/distfiles/slackware/amd64/2.1/brzpkg-x64.run

A new set of GnuPG keys were generated for this version.
</content-body>
</message:update>

</message>
